<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Books on Tidbits</title><link>jack-champagne.github.io/tags/books/</link><description>Recent content in Books on Tidbits</description><generator>Hugo 0.71.1 -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</managingEditor><webMaster>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</webMaster><copyright>Jack Champagne — All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="jack-champagne.github.io/tags/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Writing and reading</title><link>jack-champagne.github.io/posts/2020-06-26-writing-and-reading/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">jack-champagne.github.io/posts/2020-06-26-writing-and-reading/</guid><description>&lt;p>I hate writing. The one thing that I can procrastinate to oblivion is writing to the max. Even if it is a short 200-word snippet that is mostly easy to write, starting is always the hardest part. I have found very few ways that help me overcome these feelings, most of which do not work when I am not under pressure. My writing is like a diamond in the rough: Formed under pressure, and unspectacular to the eye until polished. It has always felt that way, through many of the friend groups I&amp;rsquo;ve been in, from what teachers have said, to what I have felt, it has always felt the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It feels almost like I am better at reading and interpreting poetry. Which is something that I find liberating to write or read, breaking all the norms and rules of prose. I find I can comprehend it better, connect with the symbolish, metaphors, short span, all better. Does not matter the scope or intensity of focus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, this writing I am doing for myself is the first journaling/writing project that I have actually enjoyed and done for my own personal enjoyment/benefit. My memory is terrible and this makes it feel like all the little details that slip through the cracks can be caught and archived and indexed. Being able to put a date or a number to the things that happen very occasionally in my life gives me a feeling of documentation and record of &lt;em>my&lt;/em> story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I fixed the DNS problems plauging my last night. Now it looks just how I want it. &lt;a href="http://www.jackchampagne.com">www.jackchampagne.com&lt;/a> for the webpage, automatic redirect from jackchampagne.com. Also started strike-thruing my items from the &amp;ldquo;list&amp;rdquo; to mark off what I have completed and adding a few things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess that all I got for now, toodleloo!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- Jack&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dyken Pond</title><link>jack-champagne.github.io/posts/2020-06-11-dyken-pond-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">jack-champagne.github.io/posts/2020-06-11-dyken-pond-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been an awesome week! Finishing the Lord of the Rings trilogy concluded with an epic 3hr movie session with my girlfriend (Wednesday afternoon). I have to say, in the beginning, it felt as though I would not be able to become as attached to the characters as I did in the hobbits. The trilogy&amp;rsquo;s different style coupled with the lack of Bilbo, the Dwarves, and Gandalf made it difficult. At the end of nearly 10 hours of movie almost solely featuring the Fellowship of the Ring, I am just as attached to the characters as I was in &lt;em>The Hobbit&lt;/em> trilogy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yesterday night, my sister and I traveled up to dyken pond to see my mother and to enjoy some time in the country. It is always so peaceful out here. The rain on the tin roof is always one of my favorite sounds out here. The new grass has been mowed at the camp and in Center Berlin, there is plenty of yard work to do!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also finished reading the book I have been working on &lt;em>Automate the Boring Stuff with Python&lt;/em> by Al Sweigart and I must say, I really enjoyed the read. I learned a lot about internet protcols (http, smtp, sms), filetypes, python&amp;rsquo;s inner workings, character encodings (I really didn&amp;rsquo;t know the world needed to be this complicated), windows command line and more from this book. I am currently deciding which book to read next out of 10 that I bought in a bundle about a year ago. Last night, finding something that I could apply my newfound knowledge to, I created a process of copying text from my laptop, to my phone using text. The full source code &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/jack-champagne/947c94b75e4acaf1b22e25198002c689">is on github as a gist&lt;/a> feel free to check it out! (It&amp;rsquo;s really short). I used the smtplib, and Verizon&amp;rsquo;s email sms gateway service to send data to my phone. I was able to have my python program get text either from command line or clipboard, send it over email to a special address @vtext.com (Verizon&amp;rsquo;s email to sms gateway) which then got sent to my phone. THis was free, fast, and clean in my opinion. Works like a charm in my opinion! The motivation for this came out of need for a way to send text over to my phone (like copy and paste) from my windows machine. On Mac, it&amp;rsquo;s quite easy as it would just be a quick iMessage to myself. But there is no iMessage on windows, so here is my alternative!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also want to note and record that me and my girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s minecraft world has progressed and we beat the Wither, minecraft&amp;rsquo;s other boss, on Monday. The fight seemed a little bugged (or maybe I lack expirience) but the Wither was acting strangely and then targeted me, killing me and destroying nearly all of my stuff (not Elytra!). I was not that upset thought, now I have truly moved on to the endgame. Also, the day before, we raided the Woodland Mansion and obtained totems of undying (which I used during wither fight :sad: ).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All for now!
Jack&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Hobbit</title><link>jack-champagne.github.io/posts/2020-05-26-the-hobbit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">jack-champagne.github.io/posts/2020-05-26-the-hobbit/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last night, after 4.5 hours of watching movies yesterday me and my girlfriend Lillian finished &lt;em>The Hobbit&lt;/em> movie trilogy. The precursor to the &lt;em>Lord of the Rings&lt;/em> series by J. R. R. Tolkien. I have to say a few things about the series so far. For one, I was surprised to see the middle movie &lt;em>Desolation of Smaug&lt;/em> have signifigantly lower (only slightly) ratings than the other two movies overall. After watching the movie it made a lot of sense to my as to why. If I had to watch that movie in movie theaters and the next movie &lt;em>Battle of Five Armies&lt;/em> hadn&amp;rsquo;t come out yet, I would have been deeply frustrated with the ending. The movie finished off on a cliff-hanger that was far too-intense for my liking. I enjoy having movies leave some to be desired so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel too conclusive but having a dragon (Smaug) moments away from descending down on a town and causing death and destruction and then ending the movie was a bit of a cop out in my opinion. Since I was watching these movies after all of them have been released, that frustration wasn&amp;rsquo;t there and actually was something I found to be a positive. The previous movie, of course, now led in perfectly to the final movie, picking up right where we left off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, I am getting some work done for AirCycler and am taking the day for myself. So far it has been quite slow and my recent Youtube ban has been a little bit of a failure. I am learning though! From my failures that is. I defeated Reddit two years ago now and am looking at implementing a better system for myself. I believe that less of the time-sucker apps and content in my life will contribute to a bigger feeling of fulfillment, better sleep, better mental health, and better motivation. Overall this will free up my time for other activities that I also enjoy but will be more informative, interesting, and fulfilling. I would like to read the book &lt;em>Automate the Boring stuff&lt;/em> by Al Sweigart. I find it could be very useful in the future for me, getting rid of the monotonous tasks that I will envitably have to do. I would also like to read the textbook &lt;em>Nonlinear Dynamics and Chaos&lt;/em> by Steven H. Strogatz which so far has been very interesting and enlightening. (Those challenge problems are pretty hard!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Till next time,
Jack&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>