<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Games on Tidbits</title><link>https://jack-champagne.github.io/tags/games/</link><description>Recent content in Games on Tidbits</description><generator>Hugo 0.71.1 -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</managingEditor><webMaster>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</webMaster><copyright>Jack Champagne — All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jack-champagne.github.io/tags/games/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I finally beat the Enderdragon</title><link>https://jack-champagne.github.io/posts/2020-05-06-enderdragon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jack-champagne.github.io/posts/2020-05-06-enderdragon/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yesterday, or rather, earlier this night. My girlfriend and I beat the Enderdragon in the game &lt;em>Minecraft&lt;/em>. She died twice and I did not die once. I went through all 7 of my golden apples, my 2 regeneration potions, my 3 slow falling potions, and 64 arrows. It was hard work getting to this point but this is &lt;em>the first time I have done it completely legit, no commands&lt;/em>. We immediately got an end city, got one elytra, and then another end city and another elytra. Earlier that same day, I finished 3 classes of mine for Spring Semester at UMass Amherst.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A list of the classes I have taken and are taking can be found elsewhere on my website. Maybe on my projects page!
As of writing, these files still haven&amp;rsquo;t been made into a webpage. Hoping after tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s computer science final project that I will have the time to fully devote to understanding ruby gems, jekyll, liquid, and more html, css, and javascript stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="some-goals-of-mine-that-have-been-achieved">Some goals of mine that have been achieved&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;del>1. Excel in your classes for your freshman year.&lt;/del>
&lt;del>2. Make some really great friends that are interested in what you&amp;rsquo;re interested&lt;/del>
&lt;del>3. Learn more&lt;/del>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="some-goals-for-the-summer">Some goals for the summer&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Get Bubbles up and running with a GUI ✔️&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stay in touch with friends all over ✔️&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Learn even more ✔️&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Talk soon,
Jack&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>