<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Ruby &amp; Jekyll on Tidbits</title><link>https://jack-champagne.github.io/tags/ruby-jekyll/</link><description>Recent content in Ruby &amp; Jekyll on Tidbits</description><generator>Hugo 0.71.1 -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</managingEditor><webMaster>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</webMaster><copyright>Jack Champagne — All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jack-champagne.github.io/tags/ruby-jekyll/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>An update about this site</title><link>https://jack-champagne.github.io/posts/2020-05-13-site-update-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jack-champagne.github.io/posts/2020-05-13-site-update-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi! This is Jack. Just writing a short update on the site itself and what&amp;rsquo;s going on behind the scenes =]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been working hard at getting this website viewable to the public and was originally planning on using Github pages with Jekyll. Jekyll is awesome and has a lot of uses for building static sites and blogs just like this. Unfortunately, properly installing a ruby development environment was not a trivial task! I tried many guides but alas there was no success. (Jekyll&amp;rsquo;s guide, Mike Dane&amp;rsquo;s guide on Youtube, a few others that fleet my memory as of right now)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are lots of ways of installing and managing your installs of Ruby and each one I tried came with its own set of difficulties. (Rbenv, base install) and there are a lot of tools and &amp;lsquo;gems&amp;rsquo; that ruby uses for jekyll and github pages. Between bundler, rbenv, and my setup (Windows subsystem for linux running Ubuntu 20.04) I decided that I should re-evaluate my options.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the past I have researched static site generators for a short stint at a company called &lt;em>Novice Games&lt;/em> (Summer 2019) with my high school classmates of Jack Roche and Nate Romanelli. The two most popular ones that I found were Jeykll and Hugo. When I came to revaluate this site&amp;rsquo;s future in development, Hugo became what is now my main focus to get this published.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I intend on publishing this site using Hugo (written in the go programming language) and have CI taken care of through Github actions (if possible)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do not know much CI at the moment but the CI setup on the UMass-Makerspace&amp;rsquo;s blog was something that I saw real power in and will attempt to apply it to many problems in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anywho, the makerspace wrapped up activities for the semester and we ended on a good note as a team. I am looking forward to the summer, getting to spend a little time with my girlfriend, working at AirCycler© (which I will be doing remotely, woohoo!), doing some manual labor in Berlin, NY for my family (Dyken Pond &amp;amp; Center Berlin), and taking care of stuff at home in Duxbury.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hope this was a good read if you were curious!
Talk soon,
Jack&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>