<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Self-improvement on Tidbits</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/tags/self-improvement/</link><description>Recent content in Self-improvement on Tidbits</description><generator>Hugo 0.71.1 -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</managingEditor><webMaster>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</webMaster><copyright>Jack Champagne — All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackchampagne.com/tags/self-improvement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Priorities &amp; Youtube</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-06-07-priorities/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-06-07-priorities/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="youtube-uses-too-much-of-my-time">Youtube uses too much of my time.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>And I am very aware of it. About five days ago, I made a promise to myself after my last experiment with &lt;em>quitting&lt;/em> youtube failed. I thought that I would be able to curb my Youtube habit by limiting myself to only watching what I came to the site to watch. This way I would not browse and fall victim to their powerful recommendation algorithm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This failed, and it failed by slow loosening of the rules and gradual slippage back into prior habits. Because of this, I made a decision to &lt;strong>stop&lt;/strong> watching Youtube completely for the time being. This means I cannot go on my laptop, cannot go on the app, cannot watch it on the Tv, and cannot watch a quick video that a friend may have sent me. It is a strict ban for probably forever. If I ever wanted to use the platform again, I am thinking of a couple of ways that I could do so in a completely non-addictive and fully informative matter. One method is that I must download the videos (that I was thinking of watching) first on to my device to seperate myself from the platform. I would not be allowed to let Youtube&amp;rsquo;s algorithm serve me what to watch but instead I must know it beforehand. This will be far into the future where I can live completely seperate from the need to watch video.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On another note, I have been reading &lt;em>Automate the Boring Stuff with Python&lt;/em> by Al Sweigart (which I will abbrv. as ABSP) and so far I have really enjoyed it. I am currently on the filesystem chapter and the section that details how to use python to compress (&amp;ldquo;zip&amp;rdquo;) files. I am looking forward to later chapters, particularly the ones on webscraping and &lt;em>sending emails and texts&lt;/em> 😮 with python. Last night, on a short call with my friend Matt Keating, we discussed python and a few programming things over the phone while I toured the cathedral that he was building on the ski guys minecraft server. He reminded me of a website that I have been fond of but have only now come back to: &lt;a href="https://projecteuler.net">Project Euler&lt;/a> is a collection of programming puzzles on algorithms, data-structures, optimization and more. Solving the problems it presents is a unique challenge (much like &lt;a href="https://www.codeabbey.com/">Code Abbey&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://code.golf/">Code Golf&lt;/a>) that is rewarding. I have signed back up and hopefully the python that I have learned from this book, I can properly apply for some good problem solving.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="priorites">Priorites&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A list of priorities is always important, especially for the person who likes to work on a thousand other problems before solving the big daunting problem that has been hanging over their head for weeks (me). I read an article this morning from Harvard Business Review about self-sabotaging behaviours which is what has inspired this section. So here is my current list of priorities to myself:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>My Health is most important and I think that focusing on this is one of the most valuable things I can do for myself. (Sleep, excersize, hygiene)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Staying away from all the time wasters (Youtube, Snapchat, etc&amp;hellip;) and instead replacing them with something else, like reading out of ABSP.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spending quality time with those around me (Family, friends, and my girlfriend)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keeping my room clean and establishing a good routine&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>And priorities to others:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Get BubblesGUI working with a usable GUI for AirCycler (Simulator, Debugger, Testing)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Get a roof on the 1623 Trailhead sign (It&amp;rsquo;s been nearly a year!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Clean up around the property (Duxbury, Berlin)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Thinking about doing a power-hour week sometime soon: One article each day for a week that I just write down my thoughts and day in great detail. Just a thought for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until later this week,
Jack&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>List of Important things</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-27-important-things/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-27-important-things/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post is meant to be a list of important things to remember and apply throughout daily life. It is so easy to get stuck in a hole and preform the same routine day in and day out. I believe that novelty forces people to grow and makes days feel more fulfilling. This list focuses on, at max, 10 core concepts that are worth paying attention to throughout each day of my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(5/27/2020)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Active Learning (doing myself) is far more powerful then passive learning (watching do)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I don&amp;rsquo;t have to do it perfect the first time, instead I should just get something down.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1% of improvement every day is better than 0% (By the end of the year, that will be 3778% improvement annually)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Getting enough sleep is essential&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spending time with those around you&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>There are more to be added and as the list goes on some may be deleted. A format to describe the dates on the list will be made in the future. *For now, all of the list items were added on the start date of this post. This will almost act like a sticky note / bulletin board for my thoughts on my path towards productivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks,
Jack&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I finally beat the Enderdragon</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-06-enderdragon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-06-enderdragon/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yesterday, or rather, earlier this night. My girlfriend and I beat the Enderdragon in the game &lt;em>Minecraft&lt;/em>. She died twice and I did not die once. I went through all 7 of my golden apples, my 2 regeneration potions, my 3 slow falling potions, and 64 arrows. It was hard work getting to this point but this is &lt;em>the first time I have done it completely legit, no commands&lt;/em>. We immediately got an end city, got one elytra, and then another end city and another elytra. Earlier that same day, I finished 3 classes of mine for Spring Semester at UMass Amherst.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A list of the classes I have taken and are taking can be found elsewhere on my website. Maybe on my projects page!
As of writing, these files still haven&amp;rsquo;t been made into a webpage. Hoping after tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s computer science final project that I will have the time to fully devote to understanding ruby gems, jekyll, liquid, and more html, css, and javascript stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="some-goals-of-mine-that-have-been-achieved">Some goals of mine that have been achieved&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;del>1. Excel in your classes for your freshman year.&lt;/del>
&lt;del>2. Make some really great friends that are interested in what you&amp;rsquo;re interested&lt;/del>
&lt;del>3. Learn more&lt;/del>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="some-goals-for-the-summer">Some goals for the summer&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Get Bubbles up and running with a GUI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stay in touch with friends all over&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Learn even more&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Talk soon,
Jack&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>