<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Personal on Tidbits</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in Personal on Tidbits</description><generator>Hugo 0.71.1 -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</managingEditor><webMaster>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</webMaster><copyright>Jack Champagne — All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackchampagne.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Writing and reading</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-06-26-writing-and-reading/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-06-26-writing-and-reading/</guid><description>&lt;p>I hate writing. The one thing that I can procrastinate to oblivion is writing to the max. Even if it is a short 200-word snippet that is mostly easy to write, starting is always the hardest part. I have found very few ways that help me overcome these feelings, most of which do not work when I am not under pressure. My writing is like a diamond in the rough: Formed under pressure, and unspectacular to the eye until polished. It has always felt that way, through many of the friend groups I&amp;rsquo;ve been in, from what teachers have said, to what I have felt, it has always felt the same.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It feels almost like I am better at reading and interpreting poetry. Which is something that I find liberating to write or read, breaking all the norms and rules of prose. I find I can comprehend it better, connect with the symbolish, metaphors, short span, all better. Does not matter the scope or intensity of focus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That being said, this writing I am doing for myself is the first journaling/writing project that I have actually enjoyed and done for my own personal enjoyment/benefit. My memory is terrible and this makes it feel like all the little details that slip through the cracks can be caught and archived and indexed. Being able to put a date or a number to the things that happen very occasionally in my life gives me a feeling of documentation and record of &lt;em>my&lt;/em> story.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I fixed the DNS problems plauging my last night. Now it looks just how I want it. &lt;a href="http://www.jackchampagne.com">www.jackchampagne.com&lt;/a> for the webpage, automatic redirect from jackchampagne.com. Also started strike-thruing my items from the &amp;ldquo;list&amp;rdquo; to mark off what I have completed and adding a few things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I guess that all I got for now, toodleloo!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>- Jack&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What working from home is like</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-06-25-working-from-home/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-06-25-working-from-home/</guid><description>&lt;p>Working from home has been a big challenge during Coronavirus. Mainly because the lack of a dedicated space that I must work in but also because of the sociality of working from home. It is &lt;em>easy&lt;/em> to stop work at 2 and hang out with friends or my girlfriend and veg out for the rest of the day. It is &lt;em>easy&lt;/em> to get distracted from what I was doing, it is easy to go downstairs and have a bite to eat and read an article. All of these easy things make something simple, like sitting down and typing at a computer hard. It has made me soft; I am complacent with my own laziness, sloth, and ability to &amp;ldquo;not work as hard&amp;rdquo; during these times and I feel as though I have mostly myself to blame. I remember working in a kitchen at the Milepost restaurant for a year before I landed my current job at AirCycler (which is a whole other story) and it was honest work. I remember coming home some night, smelling like a rotting garbage bin and thinking to myself, &amp;ldquo;Wow, I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to get into the shower and crawl into bed, my body hurts and that was a hell of a day.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are things that I am grateful for and some things that I would like to change. Change doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen immediately though, it happens gradually, through consistent effort. Instead of making a 100% improvement on my life today, making a 1% improvement every day for a hundred days will net me 270% change in wellbeing. The second one is far more sustainable (and is another beautiful example of compound interest). My good friend Henry popped into my mind as I am writing this because he wasn&amp;rsquo;t hanging out with the gang earlier today. He works very hard and it is something that I admire. 40 hours a week, waking up at 6:30am, all things that don&amp;rsquo;t seem in reach to me but things that are very attainable through lifestyle changes. Althought right now, maybe this is procrastination with the work that I should be pursuing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Earlier this day, Russell, Luke, Hannah, Dylan, Sam, Lillian, and I went to Dylan&amp;rsquo;s house in Saquish and relaxed on the beach. I was a great day with lots of grilled food, tubing, boating, talking with friends, and playing cornhole. The weather was perfect and it was entertaining to catch up with friends and just do whatever I wanted. I did not get sunburnt surprisingly and I was also very akeen to going swimming even though I didn&amp;rsquo;t bring a proper bathing suit. This is part of the reason why I am writing this. Today was fulfilling, but at the expense of my schedule and routine. I am tired in a good way but yet there is still work left undone. Bubbles needs to be finished and I want to move on from my demons of design and old outdated frameworks (.NET Framework 4.5 and Winforms). I have ideas for the stock market, self-automation, personal business that I want to pursue but do not want to cut my ties at AirCycler. I have enjoyed AirCycler very much and have had a pleasure working on the BATS project as well as this project (Bubbles) I am working on right now. It has been a fulfilling and rewarding expirience that has brought me great people, cool projects, and good connections and I am grateful. I am a bit rambly by now but in some ways I do wish I could go back to the office because I miss interacting with those coworkers. I do miss school because of my friends, the makerspace, and my classes/dorm living. This is the sacrifice that I make.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some good news and updates about father&amp;rsquo;s day and life:
My dad and I added a roof to the eagle scout sign project on fathers day. This came as a sign of relief and as one thing less to pester my (and my dad&amp;rsquo;s) thoughts at night. Sally was delighted to see that I had added it and it marked for me on of the last few things that I felt hanging over me from long before this whole thing started.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am now beginning to realize at this very moment that to make adding pictures to this blog (which I have really wanted to do) making a python script that automates the process of implementing it onto the blog would be really nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Continuing: My grandmother&amp;rsquo;s birthday was recent and, as a surprise, my dad, Hailey, Lillian, and I decided to head out to her and as a surprise for dinner. We ate at Jae&amp;rsquo;s and I drove the entire way there (We met my dad at intersection between 44 and 495 to drop off the Jeep Grand Cherokee). Right when I was about to turn left and head up the hill to the hotel that Jae&amp;rsquo;s in under, I had a problem with the transmission. When I gave the car power, it seemed like the tranmission wasn&amp;rsquo;t enganging and the car wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to get into drive. I was able to get it to pop and make it up the hill but 3/4 up the hill, the same thing happened again. This is when I became concerned. I shifted into four-wheel drive and was able to get it to catch again and made it to the hotel parking lot. We all got out of the car and my dad wanted to check on the transmission to see if we were going to need to make alternate plans going home. Reverse still worked fine but my dad, 4-wheel or no 4-wheel, was not able to get the transmission to engage. After 336,000 miles, the iconic 2009 GMC Yukon was dead. It was in the shop for new brake calipers (It still had the original!!) just that weekend and now we were stranded 3 hours from home at my grandmother&amp;rsquo;s birthday dinner. We went in and had a delicious and funny dinner at Jae&amp;rsquo;s. My grandmother, her sister Lynn, my Aunt Suzanne and JG sat at one table and we sat a table right next to them, but slightly apart. I ordered a burger and picked at everyone else orders. My Aunt Suzanne drove us to the Jeep Grand Cherokee in the hotel parking lot to get us home that night and we played crosswords in the car. My dad began the process of purchasing a car and intended on purchasing a car the day before this all happened. Yesterday, he finally purchased the car he wanted, a pickup truck, something that I think is a really good purchase. I have not driven it yet, nor sat in the interior, but when I dropped him off at the dealership to drive it home, the interior looked really nice. This car should last him a while&amp;hellip; I hope.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Minecraft 1.16 and 1.16.1 came out on the 23rd and 24th respectively and Lillian and I have been playing them nonstop. I have been busy with the multi-item sorter (so neccessary) while she&amp;rsquo;s been gathering some netherrite. I updated both of my servers and started contemplating a dedicated piece of hardware for all of this and for other projects I am interested in doing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also of note: I migrated back to Github pages because of the website bloat that Netlify was causing. To properly use netlify, I would have to added a few things that I did not want. I want this site to be lightweight (other than the photos I guess) and want each aspect to be tightly controlled. It was a fairly smooth process in my opinion.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyways, I think I have put off work long enough, or maybe I&amp;rsquo;m ready to just give up for the night and call it a day. Who knows?? (me, calling it a day)
Till next time,
Jack&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also just want to say briefly that moments ago (you can look at commits now, I found the www. subdomain was not working, currently trying to fix)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Birthday 2020</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-06-16-birthday-recently/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-06-16-birthday-recently/</guid><description>&lt;p>This past weekend was my birthday weekend and I got home from staying at my moms on the 13th. When we were up there we did a tremendous amount of yardwork. When I got home, my grandmother was down to visit. I learned how to make her incredible Kahlua cheesecake and spent time with her catching up. My dad announced on the 13th or the 14th that getting a dog this fall is almost certain. On the 14th, I got a terrible sunburn when me and my girlfriend went out to Saquish to look for moon snails and have a bit of a picnic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On my birthday I recieved two gifts that I am looking forward to using. The first is an apple watch, which I am wearing right now. The second is a Kindle, which I would like to use to read in bed at night instead of my phone screen. Hopefully the display is not backlit like a normal lcd display and the tablet is suitable for nighttime reading. I also recieved new shoes from my mom which I have wanted badly these past couple of weeks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As I get older, a birthday just feels like another normal day. If I was asked by someone how old I am, I&amp;rsquo;d probably respond with 18 accidentally still. This is the reality but fortunately I have not gotten to the point where I say an age from two years ago. I have found some difficulty and trouble trying to motivate to do work. The tasks that I have set out at AirCycler seem very doable and are broken up into bite size chunks but I find the work to be less interesting than that which I decide to do for my own personal improvement.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some things I wanted to jot down for some note taking:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I started the cryptography and micro/macro economics course on Khan Academy earlier this summer. And have not been doing that recently. (At one point I found myself needing pen and paper to organize my thoughts for the cryptography and econ quizzes, which made it more difficult to do before bed and such)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I also have many other books I would like to read and a Scientific American magazine to get through as well. (10 python books to read)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;del>I also want to note that my python script for sending me text from my computer does not work now for unknown reasons. I am unable to connect to gmail&amp;rsquo;s smtp server.&lt;/del>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;del>I have not watched youtube in weeks&amp;hellip; I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how long it has been but life has felt more fulfilling, busy, and peaceful recently. I feel like I am taking care of the people around me better and sometimes I feel like I am taking care of myself better (although this morning I lay in bed for nearly an hour, a habit that I am going to start to break)&lt;/del>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to start reading my next python book on my kindle&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to clean the garage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;del>I want to put a roof on the Green&amp;rsquo;s Harbor trailhead sign (for my Eagle Scout project)&lt;/del>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to get enough sleep and exercise every day! (Can track these things now using my apple watch)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to work 20 hours a week consistently and put away 25% of everything that I make.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to get more nighttime photography (Was about to last night but instead wrote a summary of campus&amp;rsquo; plans to repopulate to my friends)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to clean my room again, there is too much on the walls&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to set up a little stand at the base of my bed for a projector setup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to write more of these posts. (Am wondering right now if having this private information exposed is a privacy concern of mine.)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to create a comprehensive todo list focused around my health&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to clean out the garage&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to set up an r-pi cluster compute server&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to get my part 107&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to play more mincraft with my girlfriend&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to spend more time on discord calls with friend and in-person risk-mitigated hangouts&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to spend more time around Lillian&amp;rsquo;s family to connect more&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to program guis in flutter to try it out&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to learn options and market information through Cboe and others&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to play guitar more&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to automate more of my life&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to plan out Dyken pond trips with my friends this summer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to bike more.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to go to bed earlier and get more sleep.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to have more time? Make more time&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to camp and go on more hikes&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to &lt;em>clean&lt;/em> my mom&amp;rsquo;s car&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to see moon snails&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to start my web programming course again on khan academy&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to continue my python code-academy course (or find a different service)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to continue learning c and c++&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>( 6-25-2020 )&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I want to give myself more time&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to be the best that I can be.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I want to get right out of bed and wake up earlier (8am)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I want a lot of things in life. And it always seems like there&amp;rsquo;s just not enought time. One small thing at a time though, and I know it will get done. I know it will.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This could have a ton of tags but because of the nature of this list, I think I am going to keep it with only these.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Till next time,
- Jack&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dyken Pond</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-06-11-dyken-pond-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-06-11-dyken-pond-2/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been an awesome week! Finishing the Lord of the Rings trilogy concluded with an epic 3hr movie session with my girlfriend (Wednesday afternoon). I have to say, in the beginning, it felt as though I would not be able to become as attached to the characters as I did in the hobbits. The trilogy&amp;rsquo;s different style coupled with the lack of Bilbo, the Dwarves, and Gandalf made it difficult. At the end of nearly 10 hours of movie almost solely featuring the Fellowship of the Ring, I am just as attached to the characters as I was in &lt;em>The Hobbit&lt;/em> trilogy.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yesterday night, my sister and I traveled up to dyken pond to see my mother and to enjoy some time in the country. It is always so peaceful out here. The rain on the tin roof is always one of my favorite sounds out here. The new grass has been mowed at the camp and in Center Berlin, there is plenty of yard work to do!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also finished reading the book I have been working on &lt;em>Automate the Boring Stuff with Python&lt;/em> by Al Sweigart and I must say, I really enjoyed the read. I learned a lot about internet protcols (http, smtp, sms), filetypes, python&amp;rsquo;s inner workings, character encodings (I really didn&amp;rsquo;t know the world needed to be this complicated), windows command line and more from this book. I am currently deciding which book to read next out of 10 that I bought in a bundle about a year ago. Last night, finding something that I could apply my newfound knowledge to, I created a process of copying text from my laptop, to my phone using text. The full source code &lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/jack-champagne/947c94b75e4acaf1b22e25198002c689">is on github as a gist&lt;/a> feel free to check it out! (It&amp;rsquo;s really short). I used the smtplib, and Verizon&amp;rsquo;s email sms gateway service to send data to my phone. I was able to have my python program get text either from command line or clipboard, send it over email to a special address @vtext.com (Verizon&amp;rsquo;s email to sms gateway) which then got sent to my phone. THis was free, fast, and clean in my opinion. Works like a charm in my opinion! The motivation for this came out of need for a way to send text over to my phone (like copy and paste) from my windows machine. On Mac, it&amp;rsquo;s quite easy as it would just be a quick iMessage to myself. But there is no iMessage on windows, so here is my alternative!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also want to note and record that me and my girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s minecraft world has progressed and we beat the Wither, minecraft&amp;rsquo;s other boss, on Monday. The fight seemed a little bugged (or maybe I lack expirience) but the Wither was acting strangely and then targeted me, killing me and destroying nearly all of my stuff (not Elytra!). I was not that upset thought, now I have truly moved on to the endgame. Also, the day before, we raided the Woodland Mansion and obtained totems of undying (which I used during wither fight :sad: ).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All for now!
Jack&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Priorities &amp; Youtube</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-06-07-priorities/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-06-07-priorities/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="youtube-uses-too-much-of-my-time">Youtube uses too much of my time.&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>And I am very aware of it. About five days ago, I made a promise to myself after my last experiment with &lt;em>quitting&lt;/em> youtube failed. I thought that I would be able to curb my Youtube habit by limiting myself to only watching what I came to the site to watch. This way I would not browse and fall victim to their powerful recommendation algorithm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This failed, and it failed by slow loosening of the rules and gradual slippage back into prior habits. Because of this, I made a decision to &lt;strong>stop&lt;/strong> watching Youtube completely for the time being. This means I cannot go on my laptop, cannot go on the app, cannot watch it on the Tv, and cannot watch a quick video that a friend may have sent me. It is a strict ban for probably forever. If I ever wanted to use the platform again, I am thinking of a couple of ways that I could do so in a completely non-addictive and fully informative matter. One method is that I must download the videos (that I was thinking of watching) first on to my device to seperate myself from the platform. I would not be allowed to let Youtube&amp;rsquo;s algorithm serve me what to watch but instead I must know it beforehand. This will be far into the future where I can live completely seperate from the need to watch video.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On another note, I have been reading &lt;em>Automate the Boring Stuff with Python&lt;/em> by Al Sweigart (which I will abbrv. as ABSP) and so far I have really enjoyed it. I am currently on the filesystem chapter and the section that details how to use python to compress (&amp;ldquo;zip&amp;rdquo;) files. I am looking forward to later chapters, particularly the ones on webscraping and &lt;em>sending emails and texts&lt;/em> 😮 with python. Last night, on a short call with my friend Matt Keating, we discussed python and a few programming things over the phone while I toured the cathedral that he was building on the ski guys minecraft server. He reminded me of a website that I have been fond of but have only now come back to: &lt;a href="https://projecteuler.net">Project Euler&lt;/a> is a collection of programming puzzles on algorithms, data-structures, optimization and more. Solving the problems it presents is a unique challenge (much like &lt;a href="https://www.codeabbey.com/">Code Abbey&lt;/a> or &lt;a href="https://code.golf/">Code Golf&lt;/a>) that is rewarding. I have signed back up and hopefully the python that I have learned from this book, I can properly apply for some good problem solving.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="priorites">Priorites&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A list of priorities is always important, especially for the person who likes to work on a thousand other problems before solving the big daunting problem that has been hanging over their head for weeks (me). I read an article this morning from Harvard Business Review about self-sabotaging behaviours which is what has inspired this section. So here is my current list of priorities to myself:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>My Health is most important and I think that focusing on this is one of the most valuable things I can do for myself. (Sleep, excersize, hygiene)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Staying away from all the time wasters (Youtube, Snapchat, etc&amp;hellip;) and instead replacing them with something else, like reading out of ABSP.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spending quality time with those around me (Family, friends, and my girlfriend)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Keeping my room clean and establishing a good routine&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>And priorities to others:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Get BubblesGUI working with a usable GUI for AirCycler (Simulator, Debugger, Testing)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Get a roof on the 1623 Trailhead sign (It&amp;rsquo;s been nearly a year!)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Clean up around the property (Duxbury, Berlin)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Thinking about doing a power-hour week sometime soon: One article each day for a week that I just write down my thoughts and day in great detail. Just a thought for now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until later this week,
Jack&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dyken Pond</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-30-dyken-pond-1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-30-dyken-pond-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today was my first day back at Dyken pond for real, meaning sleeping at the camp. Last weekend, my mom and Chris ripped up the old setup around the firepit and put down sod and seed. It looks and feels so nice. Instead of stepping on rocks and pine needles every time we go outside this year, we will be laying in a bed of grass, so nice.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My girlfriend&amp;rsquo;s birthday was yesterday and even though there was a ton of stuff that we did not get to do, it was a jam-packed day. I learned that she has never really done origami before. I planned on &lt;em>possibly&lt;/em> building birdhouses, playing &lt;em>Hey There Delilah&lt;/em> by the Plain White T&amp;rsquo;s on guitar for her (wasn&amp;rsquo;t practiced enough yet!) building the lego set that Sean Henderson gave to her for her birthday, and doing a puzzle. We ran out of time! We also watched three episodes of spongebob though, starting from the beginning of course. I am surprised that I have seen every episode so far before.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Later, and at the lake!
Jack&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>List of Important things</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-27-important-things/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-27-important-things/</guid><description>&lt;p>This post is meant to be a list of important things to remember and apply throughout daily life. It is so easy to get stuck in a hole and preform the same routine day in and day out. I believe that novelty forces people to grow and makes days feel more fulfilling. This list focuses on, at max, 10 core concepts that are worth paying attention to throughout each day of my life.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(5/27/2020)&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Active Learning (doing myself) is far more powerful then passive learning (watching do)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I don&amp;rsquo;t have to do it perfect the first time, instead I should just get something down.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1% of improvement every day is better than 0% (By the end of the year, that will be 3778% improvement annually)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Getting enough sleep is essential&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spending time with those around you&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>There are more to be added and as the list goes on some may be deleted. A format to describe the dates on the list will be made in the future. *For now, all of the list items were added on the start date of this post. This will almost act like a sticky note / bulletin board for my thoughts on my path towards productivity.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Thanks,
Jack&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Hobbit</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-26-the-hobbit/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-26-the-hobbit/</guid><description>&lt;p>Last night, after 4.5 hours of watching movies yesterday me and my girlfriend Lillian finished &lt;em>The Hobbit&lt;/em> movie trilogy. The precursor to the &lt;em>Lord of the Rings&lt;/em> series by J. R. R. Tolkien. I have to say a few things about the series so far. For one, I was surprised to see the middle movie &lt;em>Desolation of Smaug&lt;/em> have signifigantly lower (only slightly) ratings than the other two movies overall. After watching the movie it made a lot of sense to my as to why. If I had to watch that movie in movie theaters and the next movie &lt;em>Battle of Five Armies&lt;/em> hadn&amp;rsquo;t come out yet, I would have been deeply frustrated with the ending. The movie finished off on a cliff-hanger that was far too-intense for my liking. I enjoy having movies leave some to be desired so it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel too conclusive but having a dragon (Smaug) moments away from descending down on a town and causing death and destruction and then ending the movie was a bit of a cop out in my opinion. Since I was watching these movies after all of them have been released, that frustration wasn&amp;rsquo;t there and actually was something I found to be a positive. The previous movie, of course, now led in perfectly to the final movie, picking up right where we left off.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today, I am getting some work done for AirCycler and am taking the day for myself. So far it has been quite slow and my recent Youtube ban has been a little bit of a failure. I am learning though! From my failures that is. I defeated Reddit two years ago now and am looking at implementing a better system for myself. I believe that less of the time-sucker apps and content in my life will contribute to a bigger feeling of fulfillment, better sleep, better mental health, and better motivation. Overall this will free up my time for other activities that I also enjoy but will be more informative, interesting, and fulfilling. I would like to read the book &lt;em>Automate the Boring stuff&lt;/em> by Al Sweigart. I find it could be very useful in the future for me, getting rid of the monotonous tasks that I will envitably have to do. I would also like to read the textbook &lt;em>Nonlinear Dynamics and Chaos&lt;/em> by Steven H. Strogatz which so far has been very interesting and enlightening. (Those challenge problems are pretty hard!)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Till next time,
Jack&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The most eaten meat is...</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-22-most-eaten-meat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-22-most-eaten-meat/</guid><description>&lt;p>the most eaten meat in the world is chicken? Seems reasonable. Poultry is everywhere&amp;hellip;
There is a lot of misinformationa about what is really the most eaten meat (goat, beef, pork) from reputable sources and what you here from word of mouth. I had a good friend tell me today that his dad always says that &amp;lsquo;Goat is the most eaten meat in the world&amp;rsquo;. I really wanted to add this to tidbits because it sounded so interesting. So, I did a little fact checking first before I wrote this article. It turns out, from what I have found this is a common misconception as people like Gordon Ramsey and commenters on the meat articles have said this repeatedly. This is not true though, poultry is the most eaten meat in the world as claimed by this &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-the-most-consumed-meats-in-the-world?share=1">Quora article&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today was a social distancing outside hangout with Henry, Russell, Luke, Lillian, and Sam outside tossing the disc and playing sports. I have finally on this day cleaned my room and sorted all of my college dorm room stuff back into my room in Duxbury. I had my moveout day
this past monday (5/18/2020) and now at the end of the week everything is in order. So clean!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>An update about this site</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-13-site-update-1/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-13-site-update-1/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hi! This is Jack. Just writing a short update on the site itself and what&amp;rsquo;s going on behind the scenes =]&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have been working hard at getting this website viewable to the public and was originally planning on using Github pages with Jekyll. Jekyll is awesome and has a lot of uses for building static sites and blogs just like this. Unfortunately, properly installing a ruby development environment was not a trivial task! I tried many guides but alas there was no success. (Jekyll&amp;rsquo;s guide, Mike Dane&amp;rsquo;s guide on Youtube, a few others that fleet my memory as of right now)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are lots of ways of installing and managing your installs of Ruby and each one I tried came with its own set of difficulties. (Rbenv, base install) and there are a lot of tools and &amp;lsquo;gems&amp;rsquo; that ruby uses for jekyll and github pages. Between bundler, rbenv, and my setup (Windows subsystem for linux running Ubuntu 20.04) I decided that I should re-evaluate my options.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the past I have researched static site generators for a short stint at a company called &lt;em>Novice Games&lt;/em> (Summer 2019) with my high school classmates of Jack Roche and Nate Romanelli. The two most popular ones that I found were Jeykll and Hugo. When I came to revaluate this site&amp;rsquo;s future in development, Hugo became what is now my main focus to get this published.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I intend on publishing this site using Hugo (written in the go programming language) and have CI taken care of through Github actions (if possible)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I do not know much CI at the moment but the CI setup on the UMass-Makerspace&amp;rsquo;s blog was something that I saw real power in and will attempt to apply it to many problems in the future.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anywho, the makerspace wrapped up activities for the semester and we ended on a good note as a team. I am looking forward to the summer, getting to spend a little time with my girlfriend, working at AirCycler© (which I will be doing remotely, woohoo!), doing some manual labor in Berlin, NY for my family (Dyken Pond &amp;amp; Center Berlin), and taking care of stuff at home in Duxbury.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Hope this was a good read if you were curious!
Talk soon,
Jack&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I finally beat the Enderdragon</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-06-enderdragon/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-06-enderdragon/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yesterday, or rather, earlier this night. My girlfriend and I beat the Enderdragon in the game &lt;em>Minecraft&lt;/em>. She died twice and I did not die once. I went through all 7 of my golden apples, my 2 regeneration potions, my 3 slow falling potions, and 64 arrows. It was hard work getting to this point but this is &lt;em>the first time I have done it completely legit, no commands&lt;/em>. We immediately got an end city, got one elytra, and then another end city and another elytra. Earlier that same day, I finished 3 classes of mine for Spring Semester at UMass Amherst.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A list of the classes I have taken and are taking can be found elsewhere on my website. Maybe on my projects page!
As of writing, these files still haven&amp;rsquo;t been made into a webpage. Hoping after tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s computer science final project that I will have the time to fully devote to understanding ruby gems, jekyll, liquid, and more html, css, and javascript stuff.&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="some-goals-of-mine-that-have-been-achieved">Some goals of mine that have been achieved&lt;/h4>
&lt;p>&lt;del>1. Excel in your classes for your freshman year.&lt;/del>
&lt;del>2. Make some really great friends that are interested in what you&amp;rsquo;re interested&lt;/del>
&lt;del>3. Learn more&lt;/del>&lt;/p>
&lt;h4 id="some-goals-for-the-summer">Some goals for the summer&lt;/h4>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Get Bubbles up and running with a GUI&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stay in touch with friends all over&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Learn even more&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Talk soon,
Jack&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>