<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Coronavirus on Tidbits</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/tags/coronavirus/</link><description>Recent content in Coronavirus on Tidbits</description><generator>Hugo 0.71.1 -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</managingEditor><webMaster>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</webMaster><copyright>Jack Champagne — All rights reserved.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jackchampagne.com/tags/coronavirus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The most eaten meat is...</title><link>https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-22-most-eaten-meat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>jackchampagne.r@gmail.com (Jack Champagne)</author><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jackchampagne.com/posts/2020-05-22-most-eaten-meat/</guid><description>&lt;p>the most eaten meat in the world is chicken? Seems reasonable. Poultry is everywhere&amp;hellip;
There is a lot of misinformationa about what is really the most eaten meat (goat, beef, pork) from reputable sources and what you here from word of mouth. I had a good friend tell me today that his dad always says that &amp;lsquo;Goat is the most eaten meat in the world&amp;rsquo;. I really wanted to add this to tidbits because it sounded so interesting. So, I did a little fact checking first before I wrote this article. It turns out, from what I have found this is a common misconception as people like Gordon Ramsey and commenters on the meat articles have said this repeatedly. This is not true though, poultry is the most eaten meat in the world as claimed by this &lt;a href="https://www.quora.com/What-are-the-the-most-consumed-meats-in-the-world?share=1">Quora article&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Today was a social distancing outside hangout with Henry, Russell, Luke, Lillian, and Sam outside tossing the disc and playing sports. I have finally on this day cleaned my room and sorted all of my college dorm room stuff back into my room in Duxbury. I had my moveout day
this past monday (5/18/2020) and now at the end of the week everything is in order. So clean!&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>